<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A letter from his highnesse the lord protector, sent to the north of England, touching loose and idle persons, and such as come from abroad to kindle fire in England, as also for the country to act according to law. VVith a list of the prisoners at Salisbury, and Excester, condemned to dye. And another list of the prisoners at Excester that were not tryed.</title>
            <author>Cromwell, Oliver, 1599-1658.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1655</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 8 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A95630</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing T7093</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E833_19</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R207536</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99866580</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99866580</idno>
            <idno type="VID">168128</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A95630)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 168128)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 126:E833[19])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A letter from his highnesse the lord protector, sent to the north of England, touching loose and idle persons, and such as come from abroad to kindle fire in England, as also for the country to act according to law. VVith a list of the prisoners at Salisbury, and Excester, condemned to dye. And another list of the prisoners at Excester that were not tryed.</title>
                  <author>Cromwell, Oliver, 1599-1658.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Robert Ibbitson,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1655.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: Oliver P.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Aprill. 27.".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Levellers --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Sedition --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Salisbury (England) --  History.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:168128:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A LETTER FROM HIS HIGHNESSE THE Lord Protector, Sent into the North of ENGLAND, touching looſe and idle perſons, and ſuch as come from abroad to kindle fire in <hi>England,</hi> as alſo for the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try to act according to Law.</p>
            <p>VVITH A Liſt of the Priſoners at <hi>Salisbury,</hi> and <hi>Excester,</hi> condemned to dye.</p>
            <p>AND Another Liſt of the Priſoners at <hi>Excester</hi> that were not tryed.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>London</hi> Printed by <hi>Robert Ibbitſon,</hi> 1655.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="lists_of_prisoners">
            <pb facs="tcp:168128:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:168128:2"/>
            <head>A LIST Of the Priſoners at <hi>Salisbury</hi> and <hi>Exceſter,</hi> condemned to die.</head>
            <div type="part">
               <opener>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Wilts ſſ.</hi> At the Seſsion of Oyer and Terminer, and general Goal Delivery held <date>the 11. of <hi>April</hi> 1655.</date>
                  </dateline>
               </opener>
               <list>
                  <head>To be drawn, hanged and quartered.</head>
                  <item>JOhn Lucas</item>
                  <item>John Dean</item>
                  <item>John Kenſey</item>
                  <item>Henry Lawrence</item>
                  <item>John Thorp</item>
                  <item>Edmund Mack</item>
                  <item>John Fryaer.</item>
               </list>
               <list>
                  <head>To be hanged by the neck until they be dead.</head>
                  <item>John Lovelace.</item>
                  <item>Thomas Sweet, <hi>alias</hi> Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage.</item>
                  <item>Robert Hartford, <hi>alias</hi> Harwood.</item>
                  <item>Sampſon Pickefat</item>
                  <item>John Woodward</item>
                  <item>Margaret Gingel.</item>
               </list>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:168128:3"/>
               <opener>
                  <dateline>
                     <hi>Devonſhire ſſ.</hi> At the Seſsion of Oyer and Termi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, holden at the Caſtle of <hi>Exon,</hi> 
                     <date>the 18 day of <hi>April,</hi> 1655.</date>
                  </dateline>
               </opener>
               <list>
                  <head>To be drawn, hanged and quartered.</head>
                  <item>John Penruddock Eſq;</item>
                  <item>Hugh Grove</item>
                  <item>Robert Duke</item>
                  <item>Richard Reeves</item>
                  <item>Francis Jones</item>
                  <item>George Duke</item>
                  <item>Thomas Fitzjames</item>
                  <item>Edward Davege</item>
                  <item>Thomas Poulton</item>
                  <item>Edward Willis</item>
                  <item>Nicholas Muſſel</item>
                  <item>William Jenkins</item>
                  <item>Thomas Hilhards</item>
                  <item>Robert Harris</item>
                  <item>John Byby</item>
                  <item>John Cook</item>
                  <item>John Hayns</item>
                  <item>Henry Collier</item>
                  <item>Joſeph Collier</item>
                  <item>James Horſington <hi>alias</hi> Huiſh.</item>
                  <item>William Wake</item>
                  <item>Chriſtopher Honeland,</item>
                  <item>Haunce Stiver</item>
                  <item>John Giles, <hi>alias</hi> Hobbe, A notorious Horſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtealer that came in on the Act of Oblivion, and one that took priſon to turn Rebel.</item>
                  <item>Abraham Wilſon.</item>
                  <item>Richard Brown.</item>
               </list>
               <list>
                  <head>To be hanged by the neck until they be dead.</head>
                  <item>Richard Thorn,</item>
                  <item>Peter Lovering</item>
                  <item>Andras Peterſon</item>
                  <item>John Vandenova</item>
                  <pb n="5" facs="tcp:168128:3"/>
                  <item> John Wilcox</item>
                  <item>Thomas Sidley</item>
                  <item>Samuel Lang</item>
                  <item>Margret Honiwel</item>
                  <item>Giles Brocker</item>
               </list>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>A Liſt of the Priſoners, not as yet Tried, and now remaining in <hi>Exon</hi> Priſon.</head>
                  <list>
                     <item>Edward Penruddock</item>
                     <item>John Jones</item>
                     <item>Edward Moringe</item>
                     <item>Joſeph Moringe</item>
                     <item>Thomas Rumſey</item>
                     <item>Richard Allwood</item>
                     <item>Henry Harding</item>
                     <item>George Gifford</item>
                     <item>Robert Brown</item>
                     <item>Simon Bearnard</item>
                     <item>Richard Humfrye</item>
                     <item>Edward Payenter</item>
                     <item>Stephen Eskyn</item>
                     <item>John Jenninges</item>
                     <item>Robert Nichols</item>
                     <item>John Shepperd</item>
                     <item>Richard H:</item>
                     <item>John Bond</item>
                     <item>Iſaack Stichley</item>
                     <item>Robert Barefoot</item>
                     <item>William Levington</item>
                     <item>Henry Hardiſwell</item>
                     <item>Carey Reynel</item>
                     <item>William Hallet</item>
                     <item>Edmond Clark</item>
                     <item>Phillip Woodward</item>
                     <item>Thomas Fray</item>
                     <item>John Ruſſel</item>
                     <item>Henry Sampſon</item>
                     <item>John Williams</item>
                     <item>Moſes Kenfeild</item>
                     <item>Robert Cordye</item>
                     <item>John Bancks</item>
                     <item>Edward Target</item>
                     <item>Leonard Carket</item>
                     <item>Nathaniel Saplin</item>
                     <item>Richard Broadgate</item>
                     <item>Edmund Vynimouth</item>
                     <pb n="6" facs="tcp:168128:4"/>
                     <item> James Combe</item>
                     <item>Thomas Mortmore.</item>
                     <item>Thomas Cawly</item>
                     <item>Robert Maton</item>
                     <item>Robert Gugar</item>
                     <item>Richard Batt</item>
                     <item>Ambroſe Cole</item>
                     <item>John Chamberlain</item>
                     <item>Thomas Uppington</item>
                     <item>William Pearſe</item>
                     <item>Thomas Cooker</item>
                     <item>William Dyimont</item>
                     <item>John Allen</item>
                     <item>Thomas Lambert</item>
                     <item>Ithroe Morthey</item>
                     <item>Henry Binſted</item>
                     <item>Timothy Maton</item>
                     <item>Cornelius Igney</item>
                     <item>Richard Reed</item>
                     <item>Richard Whitly</item>
                     <item>VVilliam King</item>
                     <item>Richard Miles</item>
                     <item>Edward Coxe</item>
                     <item>VVilliam Bungey</item>
                     <item>Richard Renfeild</item>
                     <item>Thomas Ranger</item>
                     <item>Andrew Blackman</item>
                     <item>Thomas Gray</item>
                     <item>VVilliam Martyn</item>
                     <item>Hugh Edward</item>
                     <item>James March Banks</item>
                     <item>Richard Andrews</item>
                     <item>John Vinſon</item>
                     <item>Francis Toop</item>
                     <item>John Purchas</item>
                     <item>Richard Arſcot.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:168128:4"/>
            <head>A Letter from His Highneſſe the Lord Protector, ſent into the North of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> touching Looſe and Idle per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, and ſuch as come from abroad to kindle fire in <hi>ENGLAND.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">As alſo for the Country to act according to Law.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Gentlemen,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>WEE doubt not but you have heard before this time, of the hand of God going along with us in defeating the Rebellious Inſurrection, and wee hope, through his bleſſing upon our labours, an effe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctuall courſe will be taken for the totall diſappointing of the whole deſign; Yet knowing the reſtleſsneſſe of the Common Enemy, to involve this Nation in new Calamities; Wee conceive our ſelves and all others, who are intruſted with the preſerving the Peace of the Nation, obliged to endeavour in their places to prevent and defeat the enemies intentions; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore as a means eſpecially conducing to that end, wee do earneſtly recommend it to you to take order, that diligent Watch (ſuch as the Law hath appointed) be duly kept for taking a ſtrickt accompt of all ſtran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers in your County, (and principally near the Sea
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:168128:5"/>coaſt) which will not only be a means to ſuppreſs all Looſe and Idle perſons, but may probablely cauſe ſome of thoſe, who come from abroad to kindle fire here, to be apprehended and ſeized upon, eſpecially if care be taken to ſecure all them that cannot give a good accompt of their buſineſſe, and may alſo break all dangerous meetings and aſſemblings together. Herein wee do require and ſhall expect your effectu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all endeavours, knowing that if what by Law ought to bee done, were done with diligence in this reſpect, the Contrivance of ſuch dangerous deſigns as theſe would be fruſtrated in the birth, or kept from grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to maturity. I Reſt,</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Your very affectionate Friend <hi>OLIVER P.</hi>
               </signed>
               <dateline>Whitehall <date>24 March 1654.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
